ALINE SCHNEIDER

Boca Raton, FL 33486

Portfolio: <u>alineschneider.com</u>
Phone: 561-283-9445 | Email: aline.schv@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/aline-schneider | Github: github.com/alineschneider

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with a motivation for drawing insights from data to inform decision-making, skilled in Python, Pandas, SQL, and data visualization tools, such as Tableau, JavaScript/HTML and Plotly. With an Engineering background, leadership experience and a certificate on Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley, excels at both working independently and in collaboration to solve challenging problems and drive growth.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages and Libraries: Python (Pandas, Numpy, scikit-learn), R (tidyverse: dplyr, tidyr,

ggplot2), JavaScript (D3, jQuery)

Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy

Visualization: Tableau, Plotly, Geomapping (GeoJSON and Mapbox)

Web: HTML, CSS, Flask, APIs, Web Scraping, BeautifulSoup, Google Analytics

Machine Learning: Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, Support Vector

Machine, Neural Networks, Deep Learning.

Software: Microsoft Office Specialist 2016 Excel Expert certification

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Optimization Analyst HiConversion

2019 - 2020

Boca Raton, FL

Lead the Optimization Analyst team, perform site audits and develop A/B and multivariate testing strategies for e-commerce websites to improve user experience and increase revenue; analyze the data; interpret results; create reports and present them to clients; assist Sales department with presentations to prospective clients; create automated tools for process improvement and increased efficiency.

Key Accomplishments:

- Promotion to Analyst Team Lead;
- Improved productivity and collaboration within the team through brainstorming meetings and spreadsheets to automate repeated tasks.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Budget and Finance Analyst

2014 - 2017

Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics (IBGE)

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

IBGE is a Brazilian Federal Government institution; the role involved extracting, treating and analyzing data reports relative to financial expenses; registering and controlling warranties and security deposits by third party companies providing services to IBGE.

Administrative Analyst

2011 - 2012

Vale S.A.

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Vale is a Brazilian metals and mining corporation; I worked alongside a multidisciplinary team on a project, which included benchmarking visits and travelling to Vale's operation sites, identifying opportunities to improve productivity and providing tools for better visual management.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics and Visualization Bootcamp Certificate: University of California, Berkeley A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

B.S. in Civil Engineering: Universidade Federal do Espirito Santo, Vitoria, ES, Brazil

PROJECTS

The Platinum Lyric Project

2020

GitHub Repo: github.com/alineschneider/platinum_lyric_app

- Deployed App: platinum-lyric.herokuapp.com/
 - The project aims to answer the question of whether a song's lyrics can predict its success, and exploring other possible factors that can contribute to that success.
 - Core responsibilities: building the Python/Flask web application, its integration with the PostgreSQL database, hosted in AWS, and with the Machine Learning Model; Natural Language Processing of user input to feed into the model; Plotly visualizations to provide further insights into the data; app deployment to Heroku.

LANGUAGES

• Portuguese: native

English: bilingual proficiencyNorwegian: intermediate

• French: basic